{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"not able to swallow without choking.",
					"usually conscious but has slurred speech.",
					"experiencing a right hemispheric stroke.",
					"unable to produce or understand speech."
				],
				"question": "A patient who is experiencing aphasia is:",
				"source": "See Stroke"
			},
			"back": "unable to produce or understand speech."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"brain stem.",
					"cerebrum.",
					"cerebral cortex.",
					"cerebellum."
				],
				"question": "The most basic functions of the body, such as breathing, blood pressure, and swallowing, are controlled by the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "brain stem."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Normal level of consciousness",
					"Generalized twitching of all muscles",
					"Absence of breathing",
					"No change in vision, smell, or taste"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following is characteristic of a focal-onset aware seizure?",
				"source": "See Seizures"
			},
			"back": "Normal level of consciousness"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"vertebral foramen.",
					"foramen lamina.",
					"cauda equina.",
					"foramen magnum."
				],
				"question": "The spinal cord exits the cranium through the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "foramen magnum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"generalized seizures that last less than 5 minutes.",
					"an absence seizure that is not preceded by an aura.",
					"prolonged seizures without a return of consciousness.",
					"profound tachycardia and total muscle flaccidity."
				],
				"question": "Status epilepticus is characterized by:",
				"source": "See Seizures"
			},
			"back": "prolonged seizures without a return of consciousness."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"often result in permanent brain damage.",
					"occur when a child’s fever rises slowly.",
					"are also referred to as absence seizures.",
					"are usually benign but should be evaluated."
				],
				"question": "Febrile seizures:",
				"source": "See Seizures"
			},
			"back": "are usually benign but should be evaluated."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"arm drift, speech, and facial droop.",
					"arm drift, memory, and grip strength.",
					"facial droop, speech, and pupil size.",
					"speech, pupil reaction, and memory."
				],
				"question": "Components of the Cincinnati Prehospital Stroke Scale include:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "arm drift, speech, and facial droop."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"an acute stroke.",
					"a seizure.",
					"respiratory distress.",
					"a febrile convulsion."
				],
				"question": "When caring for a patient with documented hypoglycemia, you should be MOST alert for:",
				"source": "See Altered Mental Status"
			},
			"back": "a seizure."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"hypertension.",
					"diabetes mellitus.",
					"severe stress.",
					"heavy exertion."
				],
				"question": "The MOST significant risk factor for a hemorrhagic stroke is:",
				"source": "See Stroke"
			},
			"back": "hypertension."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Rupture of a cerebral artery",
					"Blockage of a cerebral artery",
					"Narrowing of a carotid artery",
					"Acute atherosclerotic disease"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following MOST accurately describes the cause of an ischemic stroke?",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "Blockage of a cerebral artery"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"cerebellum, medulla, and occiput.",
					"midbrain, cerebellum, and spinal cord.",
					"cerebrum, cerebellum, and brain stem.",
					"brain stem, midbrain, and spinal cord."
				],
				"question": "The three major parts of the brain are the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "cerebrum, cerebellum, and brain stem."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"ask the patient to hold his or her arms up with the palms down.",
					"expect to see one arm slowly drift down to the patient’s side.",
					"observe movement of the arms for approximately 2 minutes.",
					"ask the patient to close his or her eyes during the assessment."
				],
				"question": "When assessing for arm drift of a patient with a suspected stroke, you should:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "ask the patient to close his or her eyes during the assessment."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"kidneys.",
					"pancreas.",
					"liver.",
					"brain."
				],
				"question": "Individuals with chronic alcoholism are predisposed to intracranial bleeding and hypoglycemia secondary to abnormalities in the:",
				"source": "See Altered Mental Status"
			},
			"back": "liver."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Reduced blood supply to the left hemisphere",
					"Ruptured cerebral artery in the occipital lobe",
					"Blocked cerebral artery in the frontal lobe",
					"Respiratory failure or cardiopulmonary arrest"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following conditions would MOST likely affect the entire brain?",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "Respiratory failure or cardiopulmonary arrest"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"has a GCS score that is less than 8.",
					"is older than 60 years of age.",
					"has bleeding within the brain.",
					"has had a prior heart attack."
				],
				"question": "A patient who is possibly experiencing a stroke is NOT eligible for thrombolytic (fibrinolytic) therapy if he or she:",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care"
			},
			"back": "has bleeding within the brain."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"History of migraines",
					"Slow onset of symptoms",
					"Sinus congestion",
					"Neck stiffness or pain"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following findings should concern the EMT the MOST when assessing a patient who complains of a headache?",
				"source": "See Headache"
			},
			"back": "Neck stiffness or pain"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"cerebral cortex.",
					"cerebrum.",
					"cerebellum.",
					"brain stem."
				],
				"question": "Muscle control and body coordination are controlled by the:",
				"source": "See Anatomy and Physiology"
			},
			"back": "cerebellum."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Nasal discharge of blood",
					"Confusion and weakness",
					"Unilateral hemiparesis",
					"Sudden, severe headache"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following clinical signs is MOST suggestive of a ruptured aneurysm?",
				"source": "See Stroke"
			},
			"back": "Sudden, severe headache"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"usually able to be aroused with a painful stimulus.",
					"completely unresponsive to all forms of stimuli.",
					"not thinking clearly or is incapable of being aroused.",
					"typically alert but is confused as to preceding events."
				],
				"question": "A patient with an altered mental status is:",
				"source": "See Altered Mental Status"
			},
			"back": "not thinking clearly or is incapable of being aroused."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-18-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"intracranial bleeding.",
					"epilepsy.",
					"a serious infection.",
					"a brain tumor."
				],
				"question": "A 40-year-old patient without a history of seizures experiences a generalized (tonic-clonic) seizure. The LEAST likely cause of this seizure is:",
				"source": "See Patient Assessment"
			},
			"back": "epilepsy."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-18",
		"label": "Chapter 18"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}